TYE STANLEY

Phone: (409) 622-5834 | Email: tyestanley090@gmail.com | Las Vegas, NV

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/Tye-Stanley
Portfolio: https://github.com/tyeStanley
GitHub: https://github.com/TyeStanley

Summary

Proficient in and understand HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, and MySQL along with my Projects; Nibbler, Food Planner, My Tech Blog, Weather Dashboard, Note Taker, and Password Generator as shown in my portfolio website. This experience has helped me understand in depth about how to be a successful developer. Therefore, this position will be the best fit due to my ever-growing knowledge with excellent teamwork skills, attention to detail and the ability to quickly learn and utilize new technology.

Technical Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Ajax **Back-end:** Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, RESTful API, GraphQL, Jest

Tools: Git, Git Bash, GitHub, VSCode

Experience

League of Legends API (November 21, 2022 - CURRENT) **Lead Developer**

GitHub: https://github.com/TyeStanley/league-of-legends-api

Deployed: TBA

- League of Legends API will allow you to search and utilize players data.
- Currently progressing every day for a prototype to get it deployed. Goal of this long-term
 project is to get it ready for production to distribute to other players of the League of
 Legends community to use. Ease of access to their league statistics and other players
 statistics. Statistics includes Rank, Wins, Losses, Matches played, and much more will be
 added. Building from a mobile first development process.
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, React, Express, CSS, RESTful API

Nibbler (August 2022) Front-End Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/TveStanley/nibbler

- Nibbler is an online social network to directly connect foodies.
- Gives a place to update and share different types of restaurants and foods. Where you can rate different restaurants that people personally add to the website.
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, React, CSS, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, GraphQL

My Food Planner (May 2022)

Front-End Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/TyeStanley/my-food-planner
Deployed: https://tyestanley.github.io/my-food-planner

- My Food Planner allows you to pre plan a week worth of meals.
- It frees up the much-needed time from grocery shopping since it automatically grants the required recipes needed for a week worth of meals. What I've contributed towards this project were assigning each of my team GitHub issues along with myself making sure we reached certain check points and helping teammates when needed. On top of mobile responsiveness and bug fixes to the code.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma

Weather Dashboard (May 2022)

Lead Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/TyeStanley/weather-dashboard
Deployed: https://tyestanley.github.io/weather-dashboard

- Weather Dashboard allows you to dynamically search any city for the forecast.
- Weather Dashboard accesses a weather API effectively using AJAX to quickly access and display weather information. Being straight forward and easy to use for everyone who wants to freely check the daily and future forecast.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Weather API

Goldentail Logistics LLC

Business Owner located in Houston, TX

March 2021 - April 2022

As a company, we develop, manage, and implement every facet of the business to sustain longstanding profits and growth for the company. Our leadership consists of a long line of family businesses and connection in the transportation industry for 30+ years.

Responsibilities:

- Managed freight orders, assigning carriers, and negotiating prices to reach a minimum of 10% profit as a brokerage company.
- Communicating between Carriers and Shippers so that both parties are satisfied.
- Data input and proper documentation for every freight order.
- Effectively solved transportation issues within minutes.

Humane Society-Southeast Texas

Volunteer

Went in on the weekends to assist with animal care. Fed the shelter dogs in a safe and efficient manner and cleaned out their cages.

2012 - 2014

Responsibilities:

- Monitoring the well-being of the animals from 8:00 AM to 1:00 PM. Including washing, feeding, and bringing them for walks outside.
- Successfully cultivated close relationships with aggressive dogs.
- Diligently taught basic sit and stay commands to more than 30 dogs.
- Helped more than 20 animals find their new loving home.

Education

<u>University of Texas - Austin, TX</u> Certificate in Full Stack Web Development	_	Certificate earned September 2022
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development		
<u>Lamar University - Beaumont, TX</u>	_	2014 - 2015
Course Work in Computer Science		
Port Neches-Groves ISD - Port Neches, TX	_	Graduated 2014
High School Diploma		0.444464 2011